[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 19]
[제19화]
You have to admit I played really well.
나 진짜 잘 차지 않았어?
Coach gave me that...
코치님이 나한테...
Come on.
아니
Coach.
코치님
That pass of mine...
제 패스 어땠어요?
That was exceptionally good.
진짜 좋았어
That was amazing.
그 골 대박이었어
Coach, did you see us play?
코치님, 저희 경기하는 거 보셨어요?
-We played so well. Aren't you going to praise us? -Yeah.
- 잘했는데 칭찬해 주세요 - 맞아요
Great job today.
오늘 아주 잘했어
Did you thank Ms. Lin?
린 선생님께 감사 인사는 드렸어?
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
린 선생님, 감사합니다
I'm the team supervisor.
담당 선생님으로서
It's my duty.
할 일을 했을 뿐이야
How was my pass?
제 패스 어땠어요?
-I told you. -That was a great strategy.
- 내가 말했잖아 - 이번 전술이 최고였어
You can never go wrong believing in yourself.
자신을 믿으면 된다고
We were bound to win.
무조건 이길 수 있어
What a cool win.
진짜 멋있게 이겼지
Cool as hell.
정말 멋있었어
Yes, you're the coolest.
그래, 네가 제일 멋있다
Isn't this that trendy spot with the super long lines?
여기 엄청 줄 서기 힘들다는 그 맛집 아니야?
Yes, this is a reward from your coach.
응, 이건 너희 코치님이 주는 상이야
Come on! Eat up!
와서 먹어
-Thank you, Coach! -Coach!
- 감사합니다 - 감사해요, 코치님
-Good for you!
- 최고다
I'm starving!
배고파 죽을 뻔했어
What do you want to eat?
뭐 먹을래요?
I'll go get it.
가져올게요
I've had a toothache lately, and I have things to do.
요즘 치통도 있고 일이 좀 있어서요
You guys go ahead and eat.
애들이랑 먹어요
-Fu. -Can we take whatever we like?
- 신수 - 아무거나 가져와
Babies, I'm leaving now.
얘들아, 난 먼저 갈게
We can finish it, bro.
다 먹을 수 있는 사람?
This doesn't feel right.
느낌이 안 좋은데
Surprise.
서프라이즈!
Li?
샤오리?
Congratulations on your triumphant return, Ms. Lin.
우리 린 선생님의 개선을 축하해
Let's go in.
들어가자
What's wrong?
왜 그래?
Are you feeling down?
기분이 안 좋아?
Didn't the team win today?
오늘 팀도 이겼잖아
I'm not unhappy.
기분 안 좋은 거 아니야
The kids did great.
애들도 다 잘했고
I'm just...
그냥
a little tired.
좀 피곤해서 그래
You don't have to lie to me.
나한테는 거짓말하지 마
What did you buy? Fried chicken?
뭐 사 왔어? 치킨이야?
Do you want me to stay with you,
그럼 내가 같이 있어 줄까?
or do you want to be alone for a while?
아니면 혼자 있을래?
I...
그게...
Okay.
알았어
If it gets cold, microwave it.
식었으면 전자레인지에 돌려 먹어
Don't eat it cold.
차게 먹지 말고
Take care.
알았지?
[Little Savage Tribe]
[야인 부족]
Li?
샤오리야?
I knew you were home.
집에 있을 줄 알았어요
I bought some barbecue for a late-night snack.
야식으로 먹으라고 꼬치 좀 사 왔어요
I'm not hungry.
배 안 고파요
You blocked me on WeChat.
내 메신저를 차단했던데
Can I ask why?
이유를 물어봐도 돼요?
Ming...
샤오밍이
is Jason.
제이슨이잖아요
right?
맞죠?
I know you don't want to talk to me right now,
지금 니랑 말하기 싫은 거 알아요
but I already have some clues.
하지만 내가 단서를 찾았어요
I have a notebook.
나한테 노트가 있는데
It contains my investigation results.
거기에 조사 결과가 있으니까
You can take a look at it first.
그것부터 봐요
[A Rising Star Falls: Reports Say]
[떠오르던 신예의 추락]
[Nanton's Most Promising Chinese Football Player Dies by Suicide]
[사우샘프턴 중국계 유망 선수 극단적 선택]
[Somatization of Depression]
[우울증의 신체화]
[The Michelangelo Phenomenon:]
[미켈란젤로]
[The Psychological Struggles of Perfectionists]
[완벽주의자의 심리적 딜레마]
[Somatization of Depression]
[우울증의 신체화]
[Brintellix]
[보티옥세틴]
[The IP of Spade Q] [It was London Psychology]
[스페이드 Q의 자료 출처는 런던 심리학]
[Research Institute] [This place is a historic academic institution in London.]
[연구소, 런던의 오래된 학술 기관]
[Source of the prohibited drugs] [Jason's Activities and Daily Diet]
[금지 약물의 출처와 제이슨의 사고 전 행적]
[Before the Incident] [There was only a bottle of gummy bears]
[평소 식단 곰 모양 젤리 한 통]
[I didn't go out. I hate rainy days.]
[외출을 하지 않고 비 오는 날을 싫어한다]
[It's raining today.] [Did you catch a new firefly?]
[오늘 비가 오는데 새 반딧불이는 잡았어?]
[I found fireflies downstairs today.]
[오늘 아래층에서 반딧불이를 발견했어]
[It's the rarest type. I'll send a picture to you.]
[보기 드문 종인데 보여 줄게]
[I can tell that rainy days are your favorite, but...]
[넌 비 오는 날을 제일 좋아하잖아]
[How will you get there? You should learn how to ride a bike.]
[어떻게 갈래? 자전거부터 배워]
[Hate rainy days.]
[비가 오는 날이 싫어]
[Hahaha. Tell me about it]
[그러게]
[By the way, about the gift,]
[참, 선물은...]
[can you not tell anyone?]
[다른 사람한테 말하지 마]
[Don't forget to eat it.]
[꼭 먹어야 해]
[I'll get mad if they go to waste.]
[그냥 버리면 화낼 거야]
[Jokes aside, I'll send you a gift later.]
[진지하게 말하는데 나중에 선물로 보내 줄게]
[Remember to accept it.]
[꼭 받아]
[Thank you. In the UK,]
[고마워, 영국에서]
[you're the first friend to send me a gift.]
[처음 선물을 준 친구가 바로 너야]
[Two Lin Wanxings]
[두 명의 린완싱]
Two?
두 명?
[The reason for his death] [The gift from Spade Q]
[타인을 해침] [스페이드 Q가 선물을 보냄]
[She told Jason not to tell anyone.]
[제이슨이 다른 사람한테 말하지 말라고 함]
[Different people]
[다른 사람]
Let's talk.
얘기 좀 해요
You've read the files?
자료는 다 봤어요?
I met Ming
내가 샤오밍을 알게 된 건
on a psychology forum.
한 심리 포럼에서였어요
He posted a thread,
그 애가 글을 하나 올렸는데
saying he suffered from severe insomnia
불면증이 심하고
and sometimes
가끔은
even wanted to hurt himself.
자해하고 싶다는 얘기까지 했어요
So I added him on QQ to chat with him.
그래서 메신저를 추가해서 대화를 했어요
His parents
샤오밍의 부모님은
divorced because of arguments when he was young.
어릴 때 다툼 끝에 이혼하셨대요
His father was absent.
아버지의 부재와
Because of his family of origin,
원래 가족 문제 때문에
he always had
샤오밍은 줄곧
severe psychological trauma.
심각한 마음의 상처가 있었어요
He always thought
샤오밍은 늘
it was because he wasn't good enough
자기가 부족해서
that he wasn't loved.
사랑받지 못한다고 생각했어요
If I had noticed
내가 좀 더 일찍
his psychological problems earlier,
제이슨의 심리 문제에 관심을 가졌더라면
maybe none of this would have happened.
이런 일은 일어나지 않았을 거예요
So you just said
그럼 아까
you found some clues.
단서를 찾았다고 한 건
Is it really what you said in your notebook?
정말 그 노트에 쓰여 있는 것처럼
Someone impersonated me on my account
누군가 내 계정을 도용해서
and induced him to commit suicide step by step?
한 단계씩 그 애를 자살로 유도했다는 건가요?
That person
그 사람은
did something even worse.
더 심한 짓까지 했어요
Do you remember that on Christmas
크리스마스 때
you gave Ming a bottle of gummy bears?
샤오밍한테 선물했던 젤리 기억해요?
That person
그 사람이
swapped that bottle of candy
그 젤리를 바꿔치기했어요
and added ephedrine to it.
그리고 그 안에 에페드린을 넣었고요
And as for what happened next,
그 후의 일은
you already know.
당신도 알죠
No wonder.
어쩐지
No wonder his last message to me said
나한테 남긴 마지막 메시지가
he hated me.
날 원망한다는 말이었어요
His death
내가 간접적으로
was indirectly caused by me.
샤오밍을 죽게 했네요
No, Lin Wanxing.
아니에요, 린완싱
That person is the real murderer.
그 사람이 진범이에요
Does this look familiar to you?
이거 기억해요?
The person using this profile photo
이 프로필 사진을 쓰는 사람이
is the murderer who stole your account.
당신 계정을 도용한 범인일 거예요
A butterfly?
나비...
Xiang Zi?
샹쯔?
Who is Xiang Zi?
샹쯔가 누군데요?
He is my senior.
내 학교 선배예요
He's one grade above me.
나보다 한 학년 위인데
Because he took a year off,
1년 휴학해서
he was in the same grade as me.
나랑 동기가 됐어요
I remember he loved studying butterfly specimens.
그 선배가 나비 표본 연구를 좋아했던 걸로 기억해요
Back then,
그때
it was him who went to the UK with me for the exchange program.
나랑 같이 영국으로 교환 학생을 갔었어요
That was also when I met Ming.
나도 그때 샤오밍을 알게 됐고요
Then he is the prime suspect.
그럼 그 사람이 가장 유력한 용의자네요
Did you have any conflicts with him?
그 사람이랑 무슨 원한이라도 있어요?
I rejected his confession.
고백을 거절한 적이 있는데
That shouldn't count as a conflict.
그건 원한이라고 할 수 없겠죠
Wang Fa.
왕파
I can't absolve myself from this.
이 일은 나랑도 상관있으니
I want to investigate with you.
같이 조사하고 싶어요
Okay.
좋아요
Lin Wanxing,
린완싱
I want to say...
당신한테
I'm really sorry.
정말 미안해요
At Xiang Zi's home in Lyujing,
샹쯔는 뤼징시 자택에서
he takes on some psychological counseling cases?
심리 상담 일을 받기도 한대요
He studied psychology,
그 사람은 심리학 전공이에요
so he's very guarded.
경계심이 강해서
You won't be able to get anything out of him.
뭘 물어봐도 답을 안 할 거예요
It's fine.
괜찮아요
We're going there for counseling.
우린 심리 상담을 받으러 가는 거니까요
[Psychology Counseling Room]
[심리 상담실]
Here, have some tea.
여기 차 좀 드세요
Half a spoonful of honey for you, as always?
완싱 너는 꿀 반 스푼 넣지?
You have a great memory.
선배는 기억력도 좋네요
It's been over a year since we last met.
한 1년 넘게 못 봤지?
How have you been?
잘 지냈어?
Pretty good.
잘 지냈어요
I'm glad you've moved on.
마음을 정리했다니 다행이네
I was quite worried about you.
네 걱정 많이 했어
I wanted to contact you,
연락하고 싶었는데
but I didn't have your contact info.
연락처를 몰랐어
You opened a counseling clinic only a year after graduation.
졸업 1년 만에 심리 상담실도 열고
Impressive.
선배는 정말 대단하네요
I'm not like you.
난 너랑 다르게
I'm not cut out for academics.
학문에는 흥미가 없어서
Graduating early and making money suit me better.
일찍 사회에 나와 돈 버는 게 더 잘 맞아
You're too modest.
너무 겸손하시네요
I forgot to introduce you to each other.
소개를 깜빡했네요
This is my friend, Wang Fa.
이쪽은 내 친구 왕파예요
The main reason we came here
이번에
is to ask for a favor.
선배한테 부탁할 게 있어서 왔어요
Go ahead.
말해 봐
Let me.
내가 말할게요
I need psychological counseling.
심리 상담을 받고 싶어서요
What kind of counseling do you need?
어떤 쪽으로요?
I had a student
학생 중 한 명이
who passed away.
세상을 떠났어요
For psychological counseling,
심리 상담이라면
my junior here can help you.
후배도 잘할 텐데
Why did you come to me?
왜 저를 찾아왔어요?
Isn't it a rule
심리 상담은
not to counsel acquaintances?
아는 사람한테는 안 받는 거 아니었나요?
You two are close?
둘이 많이 친한가 봐요
How close are you?
어느 정도로 친한데요?
We work together.
같이 일하는
We're colleagues,
동료예요
and he's kind of
그리고
my tenant.
집을 공유하는 사이고요
You live together?
같이 산다고?
He lives upstairs.
우리 집 위층에 살아요
I see.
알겠어
As for the counseling,
상담 건은
I need to think about it.
좀 더 생각해 볼게요
I have something to do in half an hour.
30분 뒤에 약속이 있어서
I won't keep you here today.
오늘은 이만 가 보셔야 할 것 같아요
I see.
그렇군요
Sorry to bother you.
실례했어요
Seeing these butterfly specimens
나비 표본을 보니까
reminds me of the time
우리 같이
we were in grad school.
대학원 다닐 때가 생각나네요
I really miss those days.
참 그리워요
Back then,
그때 너는
you weren't interested in these things.
이런 거에 관심 없었잖아
Things are different now.
지금은 아니에요
I'm looking forward to taking a good look at them next time.
다음에 올 땐 제대로 구경하고 싶네요
We'll see if there's a chance.
기회 되면 그러자
Let's go.
가요
Open the door for me.
차 문 열어 줘요
He's still watching.
아직도 보고 있어요
Put on a full show.
연기는 끝까지 해야죠
Didn't you say that?
당신이 연기는
Do you think he will agree?
그 사람이 우리 부탁을 들어 줄까요?
Not necessarily.
확신할 수 없어요
When we asked if we could come again,
아까 또 와도 되냐고 물었을 때
he hesitated.
망설였어요
Then what do you think we should do
그럼 우리가 어떻게 해야
to make him change his mind?
마음을 바꿀 것 같아요?
What we are doing now is fine.
지금처럼만 하면 돼요
It's working.
효과가 있네요
[A Daily Dose of Psychology: The Sweet Lemon Effect]
[매일 배우는 심리학 스위트 레몬 효과]
The Wallenda Effect]
발렌다 효과]
[See you at the studio at 10:00 a.m. the day after tomorrow.]
[모레 오전 10시 상담실에서 만나요]
He agreed.
선배가 좋대요
We have an appointment at 10:00 a.m. the day after tomorrow.
모레 오전 10시로 약속 잡았어요
Then we have a day and a half
그럼 우리한테 하루 반나절 동안
to prepare.
준비할 시간이 있네요
What's your plan?
어쩔 생각이에요?
I plan to create a personal website.
개인 웹사이트를 하나 만들까 해요
I'll have Yu Bo imitate his tone
위보한테 그 사람 말투를 따라 하게 해서
and leave lots of comments on the website
사이트에 댓글을 달아서
to attract him.
그 사람을 끌어들이려고요
Having Yu Bo empathize with him?
위보가 그 사람이랑 공감대를 형성하게 하는 거군요
If Xiang Zi relates to the comments,
샹쯔가 댓글에 공감하면
he might contact Yu Bo
위보한테 연락할지도 몰라요
and share his past cases.
자기가 겪었던 사건을 공유하면서요
The content and comments on the website
사이트 내용과 댓글은
have to be very precise.
정교하게 맞아떨어져야 해요
It's very difficult,
난도가 높겠지만
but worth a try.
시도해 볼 만해요
Okay, it's done. Take a look.
다 됐어요 보냈으니까 확인해 봐요
[Winfred Wang]
[윈프레드 왕]
[At 4 a.m., I am always the first one to arrive at the locker room.]
[새벽 4시의 라커 룸 난 팀원들보다 먼저 도착한다]
[The moment the lights come on, the empty lockers]
[불이 켜지는 순간 텅 빈 라커들이 보인다]
[look like unanswered questions on a blank sheet of paper.]
[마치 빈 답안지처럼]
Why does it seem to me
내 생각에 이런 글은
that these words aren't very effective?
별 효과가 없어 보이는데요
No, these are all moments of glory.
전부 영광의 순간들인데
How can they be ineffective?
효과가 없다니요
Yu Bo, different trades are worlds apart.
위보, 분야가 다르면 모르는 게 당연해요
The average person's attention span on a webpage
보통 사람들이 웹사이트를 볼 때
is about 6 to 8 seconds.
6초에서 8초 정도 집중해요
If they have a purpose
목적이 있어서
and want to search for something,
뭔가를 검색하려는 거면
maybe 15 seconds.
15초 정도고요
In other words,
다시 말해서
within 15 seconds,
15초 안에
if Xiang Zi
샹쯔가
doesn't see the information he wants,
원하는 정보가 안 보이면
he will close the website.
사이트를 꺼 버릴 거라는 거죠
Then what should I do?
그럼 난 어떡하죠?
What should I put up?
뭘 올려야 좋을까요?
I think we should put up some
내 생각엔 그 사람이
things he's interested in.
흥미를 느낄 만한 걸 올려야 해요
Like butterflies.
예를 들면 나비요
He likes butterflies.
그 사람이 나비를 좋아하는데
If I post these on the website,
내가 사이트에 그런 걸 올리면
would it be too deliberate?
너무 티 나지 않을까요?
That's why
그러니까
we need to show it casually.
은근슬쩍 드러내야죠
For example, we can find some photos
예를 들어 사진 몇 장을 찾아서
and add a small butterfly element
사진 한쪽 구석에
in the corners
나비 모양을 조금 넣고
for him to discover by accident.
우연히 발견하게 하는 거죠
Then what about the other content?
그럼 다른 내용은 뭘로 채우죠?
It's best to reveal your inner thoughts.
당신의 속마음을 드러내는 게 좋겠어요
But once he searches my website,
하지만 그 사람이 내 사이트를 검색하면
he'll know I'm Jason's coach.
내가 제이슨의 코치였다는 걸 알게 될 텐데요
According to Kevin's info,
케빈 쪽 정보에 따르면
he should know
자기가 죽인 사람이
who he killed.
누군지 알고 있을 거예요
Right.
맞아요
Usually, killers return to the crime scene
보통 범인이 사건 현장에 다시 가는 건
for two reasons.
두 가지 이유가 있어요
The first is to destroy evidence
첫째는 증거를 인멸하고
and cover up the crime.
죄를 덮기 위해서고
The second
둘째는
is to satisfy their twisted desire for control
자신의 변태적인 통제욕과
and sense of achievement.
성취감을 채우기 위해서예요
By reliving their actions,
자기 행동을 되새기면서
they can prove their capability and influence.
자신의 능력과 영향력을 증명하는 거죠
You are a victim of the Jason incident.
당신은 제이슨 사건의 피해자잖아요
You can satisfy this need of his.
그 사람의 그런 욕구를 채워 줄 수 있어요
He will keep reading what you write.
당신이 쓴 글이라면 계속 볼 거예요
Okay, just write about your daily life.
좋아, 넌 일상적인 글을 써
I'll look for photos.
난 사진을 찾을게
[Someone asked me why I became a coach.]
[누가 나한테 왜 코치를 하냐고 물었다]
[I think back to the first time I touched the ball, and the tremble that ran through my fingertips.]
[처음 공을 만졌을 때 발끝으로 전해지던 떨림]
[That was the moment when my passion took root and grew.]
[열정이 마음 깊이 뿌리내린 순간이었다]
[I want to help more people find themselves on the football field.]
[그리고 나는 더 많은 사람이 푸른 그라운드에서...]
What do you think of this one?
이 사진은 어때요?
It's not bad, right?
괜찮죠?
It's pretty good.
좋네요
What do you think?
어때?
The first one.
첫 번째
The second one.
두 번째
The third one.
세 번째
The fourth one.
네 번째
Let's use these.
그걸로 하자
I'm going to make some coffee.
커피 좀 타 올게
Wait, let me send them to you.
이거 주려는 거 아니야
Turn on your AirDrop
블루투스 켜고
and Bluetooth.
무선 파일 공유로 보낼게
Just email them to me.
그냥 메일로 보내
Okay.
알았어
Sent.
보냈어
I think she really likes
린 선생님은 네가
seeing you look defeated.
기죽은 모습을 좋아하는 것 같아
I like it too.
나도 좋아
I'm going grocery shopping.
난 장 보러 갈게
I'll make dinner tonight.
저녁 만들어 먹자
Based on what you said on the rooftop that day,
그날 옥상에서 했던 말을 듣고
I improvised a bit.
즉흥적으로 써 봤어요
I've sent it to your email.
메일로 보냈으니까
If you think it's too artsy,
너무 문학적이라고 생각하면
you can delete some parts.
좀 빼도 돼요
I'm heading back.
갈게요
Aren't you staying for dinner?
밥 먹고 가요
You guys eat.
두 사람끼리 먹어요
Pity is useless.
동정은 아무 소용이 없다
In a real professional arena,
프로의 세계에서는
there's no room for any flaws.
아주 작은 흠도 용납되지 않는다
That includes myself.
나 자신도 마찬가지다
But when you really stand in the position you want,
정말 원하던 자리에 서게 되면
what do decades of hard work
십수 년의 고생과
and the blood and sweat of countless people
수많은 사람의 피와 땀이
even amount to?
무슨 소용이 있을까?
Under the banner of the club,
클럽의 깃발 아래 모인
we are merely warriors
우리는 그저
united by a primitive totem,
원시 토템 아래 뭉친 전사들 같다고 느껴졌다
fighting our opponents
다른 방식으로
in another form.
상대와 싸우는 거다
Once on the field,
일단 경기장에 서면
we are essentially no different
고대 로마 검투장의
from the slaves in the ancient Roman Colosseum
귀족을 즐겁게 하던 노예와
who entertain the nobles.
본질적으로 다를 바가 없다
I didn't even have the courage to step into that cemetery.
난 그 묘지에 발을 들일 용기조차 없었다
I stood in front of the sink,
세면대 앞에 서서
looking at myself in the mirror,
커다란 검은 우산에 가려진
with a huge black umbrella covering me.
거울 속의 나를 바라봤다
Suddenly looking back
문득 돌아보니
on the life I had lived,
내 지난 인생은
I saw only misty rain
빗물에 흐릿해졌고
and could no longer see the path I had taken clearly.
걸어온 길은 전혀 보이지 않았다
Maybe football shines brightly.
어쩌면 축구는 찬란하게 빛났을지 몰라도
But it...
그 기회는
never shone on me.
끝내 내게 닿지 못했다
Where is Lin Wanxing?
린완싱은?
She went back.
갔어
Smiling so affectionately even after she left?
갔는데 그렇게 좋다고 웃고 있어?
I knew it.
그럴 줄 알았어
You just don't know how to please a girl.
너는 여자 마음을 어떻게 얻는지 모른다니까
How about this?
내가
Let me teach you a trick or two.
몇 수 가르쳐 줄게
What do you say?
어때?
Do you need me to remind you
내가 알기로
that you've only pursued one girl in your life,
넌 평생
and that was my sister?
우리 누나만 쫓아다니고도
Plus, you failed.
실패한 걸로 아는데
That's because I have high standards.
그건 내 눈이 높아서 그렇지
And let me tell you,
그리고
I'm making progress now.
전보다 많이 나아졌어
The average time she takes to reply to my messages
누나가 내 메시지에 답장 안 하는 시간이
went from 10 hours
평균 10시간에서
down to 2 hours.
2시간으로 줄었어
How's that?
어때?
Her latest reply was probably telling you to get lost.
가장 최근에 온 답장이 '꺼져' 아니었어?
Well, if she tells me to get lost, I'll...
누나가 꺼지라고 하면
definitely fold myself in three
몸을 세 번 접어서라도
and get lost.
꺼져야지
Then can you get lost and go cook right now?
그럼 지금 당장 꺼져서 밥 좀 해 줄래?
I'm starving.
배고파 죽겠어
Hurry up.
빨리
[Winfred Wang, Football Coach]
[축구 코치, 왕파]
Winfred?
왕파
When I was in the UK,
제가 영국에 있을 때도
I heard of someone named Winfred.
들어본 적 있는 이름이에요
He was quite famous.
꽤 유명하시던데요
I remember his nickname was Mr. Win.
별명이 '미스터 윈'이라고 들었어요
That should be me.
제가 맞을 거예요
A year ago,
1년 전에
I coached at the Nanton Club in the UK.
영국 사우샘프턴 클럽에서 코치로 있었어요
I've heard a lot about you.
말씀 많이 들었습니다
Not only that,
그뿐만이 아니에요
he has a lot of fans
개인 홈페이지에
on his personal website.
팬도 엄청 많아요
That's all in the past.
다 지난 일이죠
Anyway,
어쨌든
thanks for trusting me.
저를 믿어 주셔서 감사합니다
Let's get started.
그럼 시작해 볼까요?
Let's go upstairs.
올라가죠
Okay.
네
I'll go with you.
같이 올라가요
[Psychology Counseling Room]
[심리 상담실]
Mr. Wang, please.
왕 선생님, 이쪽으로 오세요
Junior,
완싱
just wait here on the sofa
넌 소파에서
for a moment.
잠깐만 기다려
[Psychology Counseling Room]
[심리 상담실]
Please take a seat.
앉으세요
Mr. Wang,
왕 선생님
let's begin.
그럼 시작해 볼까요?
Relax.
편하게 계세요
Okay.
네
So where do we start?
어디서부터 시작하면 될까요?
Let's talk about
그냥 편하게
your psychological trauma.
마음의 상처에 대해 얘기해 봐요
Are you willing to tell me about it?
저한테 얘기해 주실 수 있을까요?
One of the players I was most proud of
제가 가장 아끼던 선수가 있었는데
committed suicide by jumping off a building.
투신자살을 했어요
My next question might be
제가 지금부터 드릴 질문이
a bit direct.
좀 직설적일 수 있는데요
Why did your player's suicide
그 선수의 자살이
become traumatic for you?
왜 트라우마가 됐죠?
Is it because you were very close,
두 분이 아주 친밀한 사이였거나
or because his death was related to you?
그의 죽음이 당신과 관련이 있었나요?
It seems you
아무래도 선생님은
still don't trust me completely.
아직 저를 완전히 믿지 못하시는군요
It's fine.
괜찮아요
Let's not talk about it.
이 얘기는 하지 말고
Let's change the subject
화제를 좀 바꿔서
and talk about something else.
다른 얘기를 하죠
Talk about what,
무슨 얘기요?
Mr. Xiang?
샹 선생님
Let's talk...
우리
Let's talk about Lin Wanxing.
린완싱 얘기를 할까요?
How did you meet?
두 분은 어떻게 아는 사이예요?
Destiny.
인연이죠
I care about her a lot,
제가 그 사람을 많이 신경 써요
and I want her to be my girlfriend.
고백하고 싶고요
Do you really know her?
완싱을 잘 알아요?
How much do you know about her past?
완싱의 과거에 대해 얼마나 아세요?
That doesn't matter.
그건 중요하지 않아요
Really?
정말요?
Do you know about her family?
완싱의 가족에 대해선 알아요?
Do you know where her parents are?
부모님은 어디 계시는지 알아요?
An outstanding student like her actually dropped out of her Ph.D. program.
그렇게 똑똑한 사람이 박사 과정을 중퇴했어요
There are so many contradictions about her.
의심스러운 점이 많은데
Aren't you curious?
궁금하지 않아요?
Why should I be curious?
제가 왜 궁금해야 하죠?
Mr. Wang Fa,
왕파
from a psychological perspective,
심리학 관점에서 보면
asking a rhetorical question can indicate hostility.
반문은 적대감을 의미해요
Relax.
진정하세요
I don't mean anything else.
다른 뜻은 없어요
I just want to help you understand her better.
그냥 완싱을 더 잘 알도록 도와주려는 거예요
So,
그래서
do you really
완싱의 과거가
not want to know her past?
궁금하지 않다는 거죠?
She tries so hard to hide herself.
완싱이 그렇게 자신을 숨기려는 건
Could there be some unknown dark side?
남들에게 알려지지 않은 어두운 면이 있어서는 아닐까요?
A person's present
사람은 과거보다
is much more important than their past.
현재가 더 중요해요
I know her better than you,
제가 당신보다
and anyone else.
다른 누구보다 그 사람을 더 잘 알아요
I don't want to dig into her past.
그 사람의 과거를 파헤치고 싶지 않고
Nor do I want to pry into her secrets.
비밀을 엿보고 싶지도 않아요
It doesn't matter what she has been through,
예전에 무슨 일을 겪었든 상관없어요
because I trust her character.
난 사람을 믿으니까요
But she isn't sincere.
하지만 솔직하지 않은데
Don't you mind?
신경 쓰이지 않아요?
That's because I'm not worthy of her sincerity.
내가 부족해서 그 사람이 솔직할 수 없는 건
It's my fault.
내 잘못이죠
She didn't do anything wrong.
완싱은 아무 잘못 없어요
End of discussion.
이 얘기는 그만하죠
I don't like people talking about her behind her back.
남들이 뒤에서 완싱 얘기 하는 거 싫으니까요
Okay.
좋아요
Why aren't you worthy of her sincerity?
당신이 왜 부족해요?
What exactly did you do wrong?
도대체 뭘 잘못했는데요?
Is it because your player died?
당신 선수가 죽었기 때문에요?
Was it a coincidence
훙징에 온 건
that you came to Hongjing,
우연이에요?
or did you arrange it deliberately?
일부러 계획한 거예요?
Excuse me.
죄송해요
The school suddenly needs Coach Wang for an emergency.
학교에서 급한 일로 왕 코치님을 찾아서요
We'll come back another day.
다음에 다시 올게요
If you can't regain your emotional balance,
감정이 잘 추슬러지지 않으면
you can try meditation,
돌아가서 명상을 하거나
exercise,
운동을 하거나
or other familiar and safe ways
익숙하고
to relieve stress when you go back.
안전한 방식으로 스트레스를 푸세요
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
are you worried about me?
날 걱정하는 거예요?
I just don't want the investigation to go wrong.
수사에 차질이 생기는 게 싫을 뿐이에요
Don't worry.
걱정하지 마세요
I'm fine.
괜찮아요
Did Xiang Zi
샹쯔가
ask you any strange questions?
이상한 걸 묻진 않았어요?
For example?
어떤 거요?
What do you mean by strange questions?
이상한 질문이 뭔데요?
Nothing.
아니에요
[Winfred Wang]
[윈프레드 왕]
[I often feel that human life is like a butterfly—]
[난 가끔 사람의 생명이 나비와 같다고 생각한다]
[fragile yet beautiful. With just a little temptation,]
[취약하지만 아름답고 조금만 유혹하면]
[one can be led astray, like a moth flying into the flame.]
[불나방처럼 잘못된 길로 가게 된다]
[Your opinion is interesting. I agree with you.]
[재밌는 관점이네요 인정해요]
He finally took the bait.
드디어 걸려들었어
Who is it?
누구세요?
Xiang Zi visited our website early this morning.
샹쯔가 새벽에 우리 사이트에 접속해서
He contacted Yu Bo for a private chat.
위보한테 개인적으로 연락했어요
Any gains?
소득은 있었어요?
He showed his record of buying illegal drugs,
금지 약물 구매 기록을 보여 줬어요
confirming he was the one trading with Kevin.
케빈이랑 거래한 사람이 샹쯔라는 게 확인됐어요
The evidence is solid.
증거가 확실해요
[Jason's urine test report will be released soon.]
[제이슨의 소변검사 보고서]
[He will have to quit. Prepare the final payment.]
[대회에서 빠지게 만들고 잔금 준비해]
[The weather will be nice tomorrow. Then let's meet before 3 p.m. tomorrow.]
[내일 날씨가 좋네 내일 오후 3시]
[King's Cross Station, Locker No. 19.]
[킹스크로스역 19번 물품 보관함]
[Put the deposit in. I'll go get it.]
[계약금을 넣으면 내가 가지러 갈게]
[What kind of deal?]
[거래 내역]
[Purchase Record: Prohibited Drugs]
[금지 약품 구매 기록]
[This is our last candy delivery. See you at the same place.]
[마지막 거래야 늘 보던 곳에서 보자]
[Remember, we'll have nothing to do with each other after this.]
[일이 성사되면 우린 모르는 사이야]
You want to convict me
고작 이런 걸로
based on this?
죄를 뒤집어씌우려고요?
Kevin is already under investigation.
케빈은 이미 조사받고 있어요
You conspired to drug Jason,
두 사람이 공모해서
also known as Yang Mingsen, with banned substances,
제이슨 즉 양밍썬한테 금지 약물을 먹이고
causing his suspension, which led him to commit suicide.
출전 정지를 당하게 해서 자살로 몰고 갔죠
You can't get out of this.
못 빠져나가요
Did you forget
잊었나 본데
that it was you who replaced his gummy bears?
선배가 젤리 바꿔치기했잖아요
He's dead?
걔가 죽었어요?
Your player was too fragile.
팀원 멘탈이 너무 약하네요
Could it be that you, as his coach,
코치라는 사람이
put too much pressure on him
너무 압박을 줘서
and drove him to suicide?
자살하게 만든 건 아니고요?
He was not my player.
제 팀원도 아닌데
What does it have to do with me?
저랑 무슨 상관이에요?
He's provoking you.
자극하는 거니까
Don't fall for it.
넘어가지 말아요
Junior.
완싱
I was so good to you before,
내가 너한테 그렇게 잘해 줘도
but you didn't care about me.
날 본체만체하더니
Why are you so attentive to someone else now?
어떻게 다른 사람한테는 그렇게 잘해 줘?
It's my freedom to be attentive to whoever I want.
누구한테 잘해 주든 내 마음이에요
Jason did nothing wrong.
제이슨은 아무 잘못도 안 했어요
He was innocent.
무고하다고요
Why on earth did you harm him?
왜 제이슨을 해쳤어요?
Yes.
그래
He was innocent.
걔는 잘못이 없지
Because you are the one who was wrong.
잘못한 건 너니까
[2 Years Ago, London Psychology Research Institute]
[2년 전 런던 심리 연구소]
See you tomorrow.
내일 봐요
-Bye-bye.
- 갈게요 - 잘 가요
Junior, want some coffee?
완싱, 커피 마실래?
No thanks, honey water is fine.
아니요, 꿀물 마실게요
What are you chatting about?
무슨 얘길 하는 거야?
Sorry.
죄송해요
It's fine. No worries.
아니야, 괜찮아
You look so focused.
진지하게 얘기하길래
Who were you talking to?
누구랑 얘기하나 해서
A friend of mine.
친구랑 얘기해요
It's so late.
시간이 늦었네요
I need to hurry back and deal with this.
얼른 돌아가서 처리할 일이 있거든요
Aren't you leaving?
선배는 안 가세요?
I need to sort out the rest of my paper.
난 남은 논문 좀 정리하려고
I'm staying a bit longer.
좀 더 있을 거야
I'll get going then.
그럼 먼저 갈게요
Okay.
그래
Bye, Senior.
안녕히 계세요
Bye-bye.
잘 가
[I forgot my password.]
[비밀번호를 잊으셨나요?]
[Spade Q]
[스페이드 Q]
[Log in]
[로그인]
[Ming]
[샤오밍]
[Yongchuan University Psychology Department Student Union]
[융촨 대학교 심리학과 학생회]
[Inbox]
[메일함]
[Spade Q, are you interested in making a deal?]
[스페이드 Q 거래할 의향이 있으세요?]
[I'll pay you well.]
[사례는 충분히 할게요]
[Recipient]
[받는 사람]
[I'm Spade Q.]
[스페이드 Q입니다]
[What kind of deal?]
[어떤 거래를 말하는 거죠?]
You actually
계속 내 컴퓨터를
have been snooping on my computer?
훔쳐보고 있었어요?
Why did he get to chat with you every day?
왜 걔는 매일 너랑 얘기할 수 있고
Why did you care about him more than me?
왜 나보다 걔를 더 챙겼어?
I'm your senior.
나는 네 선배고
I like you so much.
널 그렇게 좋아했는데
Have you ever considered my feelings?
내 기분은 생각해 봤어?
Just for this reason,
고작 그런 이유로
you had to kill a person?
사람을 죽이려고 했어요?
In the end, it was because of you, Lin Wanxing.
결국 다 너 때문이잖아
I thought if I had money,
내가 돈이 있으면
you would look at me properly.
날 제대로 봐줄 줄 알았더니
But you still ignored me.
넌 날 거들떠보지도 않았고
You even rejected me.
날 거절했어
Let me tell you,
잘 들어
it feels so good to torture you.
널 괴롭히는 기분은 정말 최고야
Why should you get all the resources?
왜 모든 걸 너한테만 몰아주는 건데?
Why do you always act
왜 넌 항상
so high and mighty?
그렇게 잘난 척이야?
People like you should suffer a bit.
너 같은 인간은 고생 좀 하고
You should know that
남의 감정을 갖고 놀면
playing with others' feelings comes at a price!
대가를 치른다는 걸 알아야 해
You are insane.
정말 미쳤네요
I hate it when you look at me like that!
네가 그런 눈으로 쳐다보는 게 제일 싫어
Lin Wanxing!
린완싱!
Your hand...
손을 다쳤어요
Call the police now!
어서 신고해요
Watch out!
조심해요
Let me go! I'll kill you!
이거 놔, 죽여 버릴 거야!
Let me go! Let me go!
이거 놓으라고
Let me go!
놔!
[Police]
[경찰]
Let's go to the hospital.
병원에 가요
Okay.
네
I got it.
알았어요
Thank you.
고마워요
How is it? What did the doctor say?
어때요? 의사 선생님은 뭐래요?
No bones were broken.
뼈는 안 다쳤고
It's just a cut.
그냥 좀 찢어져서
It will heal in a week.
일주일이면 낫는대요
That's good.
다행이네요
The police said
경찰이 그러는데
when Xiang Zi was being interrogated,
샹쯔가 심문받을 때
his mental state was very unstable.
정신 상태가 불안정했대요
They suspect he may have a mental illness.
정신 질환이 의심된다고요
How will the police handle it next?
그럼 경찰은 앞으로 어떻게 한대요?
The case will be handed over first,
사건은 일단 이관하고
and Xiang Zi will be sent for a psychiatric evaluation.
샹쯔를 사법 감정한 후에
They will take the next step after the results are out.
결과가 나오면 다음 단계를 진행할 거래요
Thank you for today.
오늘 고마웠어요
I didn't expect
나도 일이
things to come to this.
이렇게 될 줄은 몰랐어요
f it's okay,
가능하다면
can I go see Ming's mother?
내가 샤오밍 어머님을 뵐 수 있을까요?
No matter what,
어쨌든
I still want to tell her the truth.
그분께 진실을 말씀드리고 싶어요
Let's go.
가요
If I had noticed earlier that someone was using me,
누가 절 이용하는 걸 좀 더 일찍 알았더라면
maybe Jason...
제이슨이 그렇게 되진 않았을 텐데
I'm sorry.
죄송해요
After it happened,
그 일이 있고 나서
I avoided it for a long time,
오랫동안 회피했어요
using the excuse that I had to find the truth
진상을 밝혀야만
before I could face you.
두 분을 볼 수 있을 것 같았거든요
Jason did nothing wrong.
제이슨은 잘못이 없어요
I was the one who was wrong.
제가 잘못했어요
I didn't give him the trust and support he needed in time.
제때 믿어 주고 지지해 주지 못했고
I didn't protect him well.
지켜 주지 못했어요
The child is gone.
아이는 이미 떠났는데
What's the point of
이제 와서 이런 말을 한들
saying all this now?
무슨 소용이 있겠어요?
For so long,
그동안
I've also been living in self-blame and guilt.
저도 죄책감에 시달렸어요
I cared about him too little.
제가 아이한테 너무 무심했어요
Every time he called,
애가 전화할 때마다
I would either ask him
저는
how many goals he scored today
오늘 몇 골을 넣었는지
or ask him
아니면
how much his ranking went up.
순위가 얼마나 올랐는지만 물었죠
If only I had cared a little more.
조금이라도 관심을 가지고
If only I had just asked him,
이렇게 물어봤으면 어땠을까요?
"Son,
아들
have you been eating well lately?
요즘 밥은 잘 먹고 다녀?
Are there any new dishes in the cafeteria?"
식당에 새로운 메뉴는 나왔어?
"Son,
아들
if you miss me,
엄마가 보고 싶으면
just tell me.
엄마한테 말해
I'll fly to the UK to see you."
엄마가 영국으로 보러 갈게
"Right, son,
참, 아들
that game console you mentioned last time,
지난번에 네가
the one you wanted,
갖고 싶다던 게임기
Mom already bought it for you."
엄마가 사 놨어
But now,
그런데 이젠
I have no one to say it to.
아무한테도 말해줄 수가 없네요
Jason didn't do anything wrong.
우리 제이슨은 잘못한 게 없어요
He was always a good kid.
항상 착한 아이였어요
Ma'am.
제이슨 어머님
Jason...
제이슨은
would definitely not want to see you
어머님께서
live in guilt forever.
평생 죄책감 속에 사는 걸 원치 않을 거예요
The living
살아 있는 사람은
must move forward.
앞으로 나아가야죠
Don't let what happened to Jason
제이슨에게 일어났던 일이
happen to another child.
다른 아이에게 반복되지 않게
Take good care of your students.
학생들을 잘 보살펴 주세요
Let's head back.
가요
I'll call a car.
택시 부를게요
I want to take a walk alone.
혼자 좀 걷고 싶어요
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪